《訴訟雙雄》前情提要
我想跟你一起工作  來皮爾遜-斯佩克特
I want to work with you. Come to Pearson Specter.
如果你只是想跟我一起工作
If all you want to do is work with me,
我可以在別的地方找工作
I can find a job somewhere else.
斯科特  我想要的不止這些
Scottie, that's not all I want.
-那就說出來  -我希望我的生命中有你
- Then say it. - I want you in my life.
結束了  邁克  我盯上你了
It's over, Mike. I'm onto you.
我要揭露你
And I'm going to expose you
撒謊卑賤的真面目
for the lying piece of filth that you are.
路易  我上過哈佛的
Louis, I went to Harvard.
我只是改了我的成績
I just changed my grade.
你作弊了
You cheated,
而如今你又指望我幫你逃過一劫
and now you're looking at me to help you get away with it.
-不是的  路易  -滾出我的視線
- No, Louis-- - Get out of my sight.
路易  他這么做是為了能從事
Louis, he did it so that he can practice
我們都熱愛的事業
the thing that we all love.
假如你不放過他的話
And if you don't let it go,
他就再也不能從事這個了
he's never gonna be able to practice it again.
你讓邁克坦白真相
You make Mike confess,
無異于將他的人生徹底毀掉
you might as well throw his life down the toilet.
你說過我們是朋友
You said we're friends.
朋友是永遠不會要求我這樣做的
A friend would not ask me to do this.
是不會  路易
No, Louis.
作為朋友  如果你不這樣做
A friend just won't hold it against you
我也不會怪罪你
if you don't.
你這一大早的上哪去了
Where did you race off to so quickly this morning?
我去見小情人了
I went to see my mistress.
她姓甚名誰
Mm-hmm, and what's her name?
重罪
Felony.
是嗎
Really?
如果我跟你說同樣的話你有什么感覺
And how would you feel if I said the same thing to you?
那得看了  她性感嗎
It depends. Is she hot?
你知道
Mm-hmm, you realize
你這是在作死吧
you're just digging yourself in deeper now, don't you?
那幸好我出門是為了送你
Well, then it's good that I was really out getting you...
這個
this.
米妮鼠
Minnie Mouse.
我從你爸那兒拿的照片
I got a copy from your dad.
應該可以和這幅大熊貓搭配上
I thought it would complement panda.
太棒了
It's perfect.
那就好  我重獲新生了
Good, because I have a new lease on life.
如果沒有你  我就沒這個機會
And I wouldn't if it weren't for you.
不止我一個人
I am not the only one
幫忙說服路易放過你
who helped convince Louis to let it go.
我知道
I know.
那你要送哈維什么嗎
So are you gonna get something for Harvey?
我也想  但他什么都不缺
I want to, but what do you get
能送他什么
the man who has everything?
你送我的東西
The same thing you got me.
一張他扮成米老鼠的照片嗎
A picture of him dressed as a mouse?
不是
No.
金錢買不到的東西
Something money can't buy.
你要什么
What do you need?
-建議  -這條領帶真得換了
- Advice. - That tie has got to go.
我都忍住沒說好幾個月了
I've been wanting to say something for months.
不是領帶的事  對吧
It's not about the tie, is it?
你知道不是領帶的事
You know it's not about the tie.
你就想耍耍我
You're just giving me shit.
自己送上門的機會必須把握住啊
We take our opportunities where they present themselves.
好了  唐娜能為您做什么呢
Now what can Donna do for you?
-我需要完美的禮物  -送誰
- I need the perfect gift. - Who is it?
瑞秋嗎  要私人一點
Rachel? Something personal,
最好是從她爸那兒拿一張照片
preferably a picture from her father.
你怎么會...
How could you possibly--
送杰西卡就要簡單優雅
Jessica? Simple and elegant.
或者狂野瘋狂  你自己選吧
Or wild and crazy, the choice is yours.
路易的話  無所謂啦
Louis? Oh, God, doesn't matter.
隨便送什么  他都會哭上好幾天
Just get him anything. He'll cry for days.
那哈維呢
What about Harvey?
沒有禮物適合送哈維
There is no gift for Harvey.
他想要的  都會得到
He gets what he wants,
沒得到的  就是不想要
and he doesn't want what he doesn't get.
這個認識  就是我能送給他的唯一禮物
And my knowing that is the only gift he'll ever need from me.
唐娜  我來這兒以后
Donna, ever since I've been here,
每天早晨走出那部電梯時都在想
every morning, I step off that elevator wondering
今天會不會是我在這兒的最后一天
if this is going to be my last day.
上周  那一天來臨了
Last week, that day came,
而哈維說"今天不行"
and Harvey said, "Not today."
我...
I...
我需要送他點什么
I just--I need to get him something
好讓他知道這件事對我有多大意義
to let him know what that means to me.
-好吧  -怎么樣
- Okay. - What?
有這么一樣東西  哈維朝思暮想了很多年
There is one thing that Harvey has been wanting to get
都沒能得到
for years, and he hasn't been able to.
-是什么  -不行  太私人了
- What is it? - No, it's too personal.
而且連他都得不到
And I don't see how you're going to be able
你怎么會有本事弄到
to make it happen when he couldn't.
不管是什么  這一定是完美禮物
Whatever it is, it'll make the perfect gift.
首先
Before we do anything else,
我想正式歡迎我們最新的資深合伙人
I'd like to officially welcome our newest senior partner,
達娜·斯科特
Dana Scott.
謝謝大家讓我入伙
I'd like to thank you all for bringing me in.
我保證  我會積極做到最好
And I assure you, I will be hitting the ground running.
這話我愛聽
Well, that's what we like to hear.
哈維  弗蘭克林·科利爾的案子怎么樣
Harvey, where do we stand on Franklin Courier?
他們周五剛宣布了收購計劃
They just announced plans for the acquisition Friday.
我想負責這件案子
I'd like to take lead on this one.
看來你的確很積極啊
I guess the ground has been hit.
給你了
It's yours.
非常抱歉
Shit. I am so sorry.
我剛在洛根出了點意外
I had an incident at Logan.
-錯過什么了嗎  -沒有
- Did I miss anything? - Not really.
弗蘭克林收購案會交給斯科特負責
Scottie's going to be handling the Franklin acquisition.
你在說笑吧
You're kidding, right?
弗蘭克林是我的客戶  我就遲到了五分鐘
Franklin's my client. I was five minutes late.
事實上  是十分鐘
Ten minutes, actually.
我不管我是不是
Well, I don't care if I skipped
翹掉了整場會議去全身脫毛了
the whole goddamn meeting to get a full-body wax.
那家公司還是無名小卒的時就是我談下的
I landed that company when they were a regional shithole,
我可不需要誰來插足...
and I don't need some interloper to--
斯科特現在是資深合伙人了  路易
Scottie's a senior partner, Louis.
扯淡呢
Oh, this is bullshit.
你的意思是規章制度也是扯淡了
Then I guess you're saying the bylaws are bullshit.
我的規章制度簡直是藝術
My bylaws are a work of art.
我知道
I know.
規章制度寫明如果資深合伙人
And the bylaws clearly state that if a senior partner
開會遲到十分鐘以上
is more than ten minutes late to a meeting,
就無權發言了
he or she has no standing.
這條規定沒有考慮到
Well, that rule doesn't take into consideration
合伙人是因為不可控因素才遲到的
a partner being late due to reasons beyond his control.
不好意思
Wait. I'm sorry.
"這條規定在任何情況下都不得縮減
"This rule shall not be abridged by any circumstance,
包括但不限于家人生病
"including but not limited to family illness,
刑事拘留和行程延誤
"criminal detention, and travel delay.
因為沒有守時  我們與動物無異"  對吧
For without punctuality, we are animals," Right?
你竟敢對我引用我自己的話  這事沒完
How dare you quote me to me? This isn't over.
到此為止了
Yes, it is.
他們仍舊是你的客戶  路易
They're still your client, Louis,
但這個收購案由斯科特負責了
but it's Scottie's transaction.
繼續
Moving on.
這是什么
What's this?
這是你能收到的最棒的禮物
Oh, it's only the greatest gift you've ever received.
比喬丹狂砍凱爾特人63分那場
Better than M.J.'s jersey
穿的球衣還棒嗎
from the 63-point game?
如果這個文件夾當時也上場了
If this folder had played in that game,
那它一定能砍下80分
it would have scored 80 points.
我都不知道這話什么意思
Okay, I don't even know what that means.
我也不知道  你打開就是了
Neither do I. Just open it.
一件普通公司的案子
A run-of-the-mill corporate case.
我不明白
I don't get it.
快看另一面的代表律師是誰
Just look at the attorney of record on the other side.
A.艾略特·斯坦普爾
A. Eliot Stemple.
你怎么知道的
How did you know?
我問了唐娜  她把一切都告訴我了
I talked to Donna. She told me everything.
-什么叫"一切"  -我不知道
- Define "everything." - Oh, I don't know.
你們在哈佛時
He kicked your ass in moot court
他連續三年在模擬法庭擊敗了你
three years running at Harvard.
你很不爽  夜不能寐
You're kind of upset about it. It keeps you up at night.
如果她把一切都告訴你了
Yeah, well, if she told you everything,
你就該知道過去十年他一直躲著我
you'd know he's been ducking me for the past ten years.
哈維  我剛說了
Harvey, I just told you
這份禮物比喬丹的球衣更棒
this gift is better than M.J.'s jersey.
如果我履行不了
Do you think I'd make that kind of claim
又怎么會說呢
if I couldn't deliver on it?
你什么意思
What are you saying?
我的意思是
I'm saying
A.艾略特·斯坦普爾今天躲不開你了
that A. Eliot Stemple is not ducking you today.
本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用作任何商業盈利行為
翻譯：愛卿遛小鳥   草草   面條打包子
翻譯：妞兒   Reginamoon   小小  王大可
校對：油炸電風扇     時間軸：憑陵新月   小式   雯雯記
后期：冰冰愛尖尖     總監：swears
本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用作任何商業盈利行為
訴 訟 雙 雄
第三季   第十三集
人人影視
YYeTs.com
路易  如果是弗蘭克林·科利爾的事
Louis, if this is about Franklin Courier,
我已經決定了
I've made my decision.
-不是  -好
- It's not. - Okay.
那是什么事
Then what's this about?
-弗蘭克林·科利爾  -路易
- It's about Franklin Courier. - Louis.
杰西卡  我要知道我為什么被排在了
Jessica, I want to know where I fall in the pecking order
-達娜·斯科特后面  -公司沒有排名
- with regard to Dana Scott. - There is no pecking order.
-我不是那么做事的  -好啊
- I don't look at things that way. - Great.
那我被排在她后面是因為她在跟哈維上床
That means I'm behind her because she's banging Harvey.
我會裝作沒聽到你這句話
I'm going to pretend I didn't just hear that.
不幸的是
Well, unfortunately,
我不能裝作你剛剛沒有替你
I can't pretend that you didn't just screw me over
合伙人的女朋友而坑我
on behalf of your partner's girlfriend.
路易  我沒坑你
Louis, I didn't screw you over.
是你自己的章程坑了你
Your own bylaws did.
如果你倆交換位置
And if the shoe were on the other foot
你奪走了她的案子
and you'd taken the case from her,
你絕不會有任何良心不安
you'd be sleeping like a baby.
那又如何
What does that have to do with anything?
好吧  不用回答了
All right, you know what, don't bother answering that question.
對我而言  達娜·斯科特死定了
As far as I'm concerned, Dana Scott is dead to me.
路易
Louis...
你有沒有想過  這些局面
Did it ever occur to you that these situations
或許是你自己造成的
may sometimes be a result of your own doing?
你在說什么啊
What on God's green Earth are you talking about?
你有機會跟新來的高級合伙人成為朋友
You have an opportunity to bond with our newest senior partner
或者永遠跟她交惡
or make a permanent enemy of her.
我要說的是  過去
And I'm saying, in the past,
你一般都選擇了與人交惡的那條路
you've generally chosen the enemy route.
舉個例子
Can you give me a specific?
立刻能想到的嗎
Off the top of my head?
潘伯頓  耶茨  科恩  達夫納  拉米爾茲
Pemberton, Yates, Cohen, Duffner, Ramirez...
這只是五起個別事件
That's five isolated incidents.
羅賓森  詹金斯  加德納
Robinson, Jenkins, Gardner.
好吧  你想說什么
Okay, okay, fine. What's your point?
我想說  如果這事你不去糾結
My point is, if you let this thing go,
你能徹底改變
you can change the entire course
你跟斯科特的關系
of your relationship with Scottie...
誰知道呢
And who knows,
或許能重新定位你在公司中的形象
maybe even redefine yourself within the firm.
人生箴言啊
Words to live by.
杰西卡  你可能就此改變了我人生的前景
Jessica, you may have just changed my entire outlook on life.
-是炸彈嗎  -是禮物
- Is that a bomb? - it's a gift.
今早的事之后  你還要送我禮物
You're giving me a gift after what happened this morning?
是啊
You're right.
你的確靠咬文嚼字偷走了我的客戶
You did poach my client on a technicality.
更糟的是
And worse than that,
你還利用我的話來堵我的嘴
you used my own precious words against me,
一般來說  我會向你宣戰  但是...
and normally, I'd declare war, but--
什么
But what?
有人向我指出  我有些不良傾向
It's been pointed out to me that I have certain proclivities
應該做下調整
that need to be adjusted.
路易  你到底要干什么
Louis, what are you saying?
我是想跟你做朋友
I'm saying I would like us to be friends.
真貼心
It's very sweet.
-謝謝  -謝謝
- Thank you. - Thank you.
-我們是朋友了嗎  -嗯
- So we're friends? - Friends.
很好  把我的案子還我
Great. Give me my files back.
什么
Excuse me?
你接受了我的友誼  還我的案子
You accepted my friendship. Give me back my case.
抱歉  路易  但這是不行的
Uh, sorry, Louis. That's not how it works.
你算哪門子的朋友啊
What the hell kind of friend are you?
我是不會接受你一條圍巾就
I'm a friend who is not going to give you my case
把案子還給你的朋友
14 seconds after you give me a scarf.
那可不是一條圍巾
No, no, no, it's not a scarf.
那是世界上最好的披肩
It's one of the world's finest pashminas.
就算是唯一一件我也不管
I don't care if it's the world's only pashmina.
案子不能給你
You're not getting this case.
那我沒別的辦法了
Well, then you leave me no choice
只能執行第19.5條B款
but to institute article 19.5/B.
沒有那么一條
There is no article 19.5/B.
現在有了
There is now.
新律師與客戶會面必須由
All new hires must be accompanied to client meetings
之前的律師陪同
by the existing attorney of record.
你個混蛋
You son of a bitch.
-你就是想找茬  -什么
- You just want to start a fight. - Excuse me?
我想跟你交朋友的
I tried to make friends with you,
你卻讓我去死
and you just told me to go screw myself.
我警告你  路易
I am warning you, Louis.
你不會想跟我斗的
This is a fight you do not want.
不  我想  而且我會贏
Oh, no, I want it, and I'm gonna win it.
到時候  你可別找你男朋友哭去
And when I do, you better not go crying to your boyfriend.
瞧瞧這是誰
Well, look who it is,
《過去的圣誕精靈》[狄更斯小說]
the Ghost of Christmas Past,
人人影視
YYeTs.com
哈維·雷吉納德·斯佩克特
Harvey Reginald Specter.
說到過去  A.艾略特
Speaking of the past, A. Eliot,
羅斯福來電話了
F.D.R. called.
他想要回他的領結
He wants his bowtie back.
如果你以前也能這么厲害
Oh, if you'd had rebuttals like that,
或許在模擬法庭上就能斗過我一次了
maybe you would've gotten past me in moot court just once.
相信我  阿奇伯德  我早就不在乎你了
Trust me, Archibald, I'm way past you.
我看也是  瞧瞧你
Oh, I guess you are. Look at you, huh?
湯姆·福特的西裝  一千塊的發型
Tom Ford suit, $1,000 hairdo.
我在哈佛時認識的那個只知道追女生的
What happened to the skirt-chasing degenerate
-浪蕩子哪去了  -他啊
- I knew back at Harvard? - Oh, him?
他在一家比你的公司大十倍的律所
He's a name partner at a firm
做冠名合伙人
ten times bigger than yours.
這么在意大小  看來是想彌補
Bigger? Sounds like somebody's trying to compensate
那三場慘敗
for three huge losses.
或者是生活在過去的人不敢
Or somebody's living in the past and too afraid
跟我在現在對壘
to take me on in the present.
怕的是你
You're the one who's afraid.
你好像有點PTSD[原:創傷后應激障礙]
I think you've got a little PTSD--
被斯坦普爾完爆后創傷后遺癥
Post-traumatic Stemple disorder.
我們現在比一場吧
Why don't we go head-to-head right now?
我很想
Oh, I'd love to.
但可惜啊  我的案子要開庭了
But unfortunately, my case is up on the docket.
但我們回頭找時間再繼續吧
But let's do this again really soon, okay?
打電話
Call me.
AYZ科技訴亞努什微處理器公司一案
AYZ Technologies versus Janus Microprocessors.
原告律師邁克·羅斯
Mike Ross for the plaintiff, your honor.
被告律師A.艾略特·斯坦普爾
A. Eliot Stemple for the defense.
-你來干什么  -抱歉
- What are you doing here? - Oh, I'm sorry.
我忘記在訴狀上寫我們律所的名字了嗎
Did I forget to put the name of my firm on the complaint?
我是皮爾遜-斯佩克特的
I work at Pearson Specter.
斯佩克特  來自哈維·雷吉納德·斯佩克特
That's Specter, as in Harvey Reginald Specter.
請陳述預審動議
I'm ready to hear pretrial motions.
請求更換律師  法官大人
Motion to substitute counsel, Your Honor.
什么理由
On what grounds?
因為他是個膽小鬼
On the grounds that he's a pussy.
-你說什么  斯佩克特先生  -我只是不知
- What's that, Mr. Specter? - I was just wondering
他的動議是否打印出來了  我們沒拿到啊
if he has a copy of his motion, because we never got one.
我沒拿  法官大人  臨時有事
Not with me, Your Honor. Something suddenly came up.
我侄女病了
My niece, she took ill.
如果家人生病  你當然該前去照料
Well, when your family's sick, you have to tend to them.
法官大人  斯坦普爾先生雖然沒帶他的動議
Your Honor, Mr. Stemple may not have a copy of his motion,
但我們有他的家譜
but we do have a copy of his family tree.
他沒有侄女
He has no nieces.
我不是真指侄女
I meant "niece" figuratively.
她其實是我的教女
She is actually my goddaughter.
她叫什么
And what exactly is her name?
桑德拉·希爾威斯汀
Sandra Silverstein.
法官大人  在過去五年里
Your Honor, that's the same fictitious goddaughter
每逢斯坦普爾先生需要訴訟延期
that's taken ill every time Mr. Stemple's needed a continuance
這個虛假的教女就會生病
in the last five years.
看來病得不輕啊
Sounds serious.
試過針灸嗎
Have you tried acupuncture?
他們太過分了  法官大人
They are completely out of line, Your Honor.
過分的是你
The only thing out of line is you.
斯坦普爾先生  你不僅不可以換下自己
Mr. Stemple, not only will you not be replacing yourself,
你還要向法庭交兩千塊罰款
you'll be paying the court a $2,000 fine.
關住他了  囚籠搏擊比賽開始
We got him. The cage match is on.
兩人進  一人出
Two men enter, one man leaves.
我們現在還什么都沒有呢
We don't have anything yet.
什么
What?
得了  你還要我替你作戰嗎
Come on, you need me to try this thing for you too?
聽好了  這可不是雷霆穹頂的表演
Listen to me. This isn't Thunder Dome.
你要去把他離開法學院后的每件案子都看一遍
I need you to look at every case he's worked since law school.
放心  哈維  我會搞定的
Relax, Harvey. I'm all over it.
那最好  因為你不了解他
You better be, because you don't know this guy.
我告訴你  一旦他明白
I'm telling you, once it sinks in
這次他逃不掉了
that there's no way out of that cage,
他就會全力出擊的
he's gonna come out swinging.
你白跑一趟  哈維今晚沒來
You wasted a trip. Harvey's gone for the night.
我不是來找哈維的  我是來找你的
I'm not here to see Harvey. I'm here to see you.
拜托了  我要說的話很重要
Please, what I have to say is important.
我對你要說什么沒興趣
I'm not interested in what you have to say.
上法學院時  我一無所有
In law school, I had nothing.
什么都沒有
Nothing.
沒有朋友  女朋友  不被人放在眼里
No friends, no girlfriend, no respect.
事實上  我的成績也只是勉強畢業
The truth is, I was hanging onto not flunking out by a thread.
看著我  我仍未婚
Look at me. I'm not married.
沒有孩子  事業根本不成功
I don't have children. I'm not particularly successful.
你為什么要告訴我這些
Why are you telling me this?
我有自己要堅持的小驕傲
I have a little piece of glory that I've been holding on to,
我不認為哈維會在意
and I don't expect Harvey to care about that.
但第一律師仍是你
But you're still first chair.
你仍能放我一馬
You can still let me out.
而且我想你應該會答應
And I thought that maybe you would.
我會考慮下的
I'll think about it.
那樣就夠了
That's all I can ask for.
除了一件事
Except for one thing.
這跟你的原告告訴哈維的話一字不差
That's the exact same speech that your plaintiff gave Harvey,
在第一年的時候
year one.
但這并不意味我說了假話
Doesn't mean it isn't true.
你認為我會讓你這樣玩弄我嗎
You think I'm gonna let you play me?
試試總沒壞處
A man can try.
斯坦普爾  這么長時間你一直躲著哈維
Stemple, you've been ducking Harvey long enough.
現在你要么打贏  要么就輸掉官司
Now you're either gonna win, or you're gonna lose.
你這次絕對躲不掉他
What you're not gonna do is avoid him anymore.
你忘了件事
Oh, and you forgot.
我查過你的家譜
I looked up your family tree.
你已經結婚了  還有孩子
You are married, you do have children,
你的事務所是業內一流的
and your firm is top tier.
拜托  我討厭我老婆  孩子就是拖累
Please, I hate my wife, my children are anchors,
我留在那個事務所的唯一原因
and the only reason I stay at that firm
就是付錢給他們讓他們別管我
is to pay for them to leave me alone.
滾進電梯吧  斯坦普爾
Get the hell on the elevator, stemple.
我可不想讓你待在我們辦公室
I'm not leaving you in our office.
好主意
Good call.
艾略特·斯坦普爾  舊相識了啊
Eliot Stemple, that's a blast from the past.
當他意識到這次躲不掉我時
You should have seen his smug face
你真應該看看他那張自以為是的臉
when he realized he couldn't duck me.
需要我幫忙嗎
Need my help?
不用  這案子我要靠自己
No, I am taking this one all for myself.
哈維  已經三次了
Harvey, it was three times.
還記得它對你造成了什么影響嗎
You remember what it did to you?
對  我記得
Yeah, I remember.
但別老想著在我不需要幫忙的事上幫我
But instead of offering help where it isn't needed,
你應該把精力集中在路易·利特身上
you should be focused on Louis Litt.
你在會議上那樣對待他之后
After what you did at that meeting,
他會竭盡所能地對付你
he's going to come at you full-bore.
我就是要那么做
I wouldn't have it any other way.
你故意挑起了跟他的爭斗
You picked a fight with him on purpose.
確實如此
Of course I did.
那你說"要坦誠待人"
What happened to the whole
又是怎么一回事
"We need to be open and honest" thing?
我覺得在這么淺顯易懂的問題上
I didn't think we needed to be open and honest
我們不需要對對方坦誠
that one plus one equals two.
我明白了
I get it.
你不希望被大家看做是我的女朋友
You don't want to be seen as my girlfriend,
所以你選擇挑戰所有人中
so you picked a fight with the biggest,
你挑了最兇最猛的對手
baddest prisoner in the yard.
如果我贏了
I win this,
人人影視
YYeTs.com
我就是勝過路易·利特的合伙人
I'm the partner that beat Louis Litt,
而不是跟哈維·斯佩克特上床的合伙人
not the partner sleeping with Harvey Specter.
好吧  我尊重你的選擇
Okay, I respect that.
但路易剛幫過我一個大忙
But Louis just did me a huge favor,
我不想夾在你們中間為難
and I don't want to get caught in the middle of it.
我不需要你夾在中間
I don't need you in the middle of it.
很好
Good.
不過
Although...
你做了什么
What did you do?
實際上不是我做了什么
Well, it's not really what I did.
是你做了什么
It's, um... what you did.
我做了什么
what did I do?
路易  你在這干什么
Louis, what are you doing here?
昨晚我收到你的郵件了
Hey, I got your email last night.
-對  關于那個  -沒事  沒事
- Yeah, about that--  - No, no, no.
收到郵件我很開心
I was happy to get it,
也很開心能做那些工作
happy to do the work.
沒有比熬一整夜
Nothing makes me happier
幫助我的朋友更讓我高興的事了
than to spend all night helping out a friend.
你整晚都沒睡嗎
You were up all night?
4:30到4:45之間打了個盹
Caught a power nap between 4:30 and 4:45.
我沒事
I'll be fine.
你都查到什么了
Well, what'd you come up with?
按照你的指示
Per your instructions,
我仔細地查看了
I went through eight years
普理查德控股公司
of Pritchard Holdings corporate returns
八年來的財政報表
with a fine-tooth comb.
這時間跨度可真不小啊
That's a remarkably long time frame.
對  你讓我查四年  我給你八年的結果
Yeah, you ask for four, I give you eight.
我就是這么做事的
It's what I do.
而且我找出了每一處錯誤
And I caught every mistake there was to find.
很好  把修正后的報表交上去
Great. File the amended returns.
走運的話
With any luck,
詹納制藥公司會一敗涂地的
Jenner Pharmaceuticals will be none the wiser.
詹納制藥公司
Jenner Pharmaceuticals?
這案子是起訴米勒貨運的
This suit's against Miller Trucking.
我之前說錯了  是米勒貨運
That's what I meant, Miller Trucking.
他們是因為什么被起訴的
What are they suing them for?
貨運
Trucking?
媽的
God damn it.
你給我發那封郵件就是為給我添亂的
You sent that email just to screw with me.
路易  那郵件不是我發的
Louis, I didn't send the email.
是斯科特發的
Scottie did.
她用了我的電腦  我完全不知情
She used my computer. I didn't even know.
騙人  她跑來找你幫忙
Oh, bullsh. She came running to you.
你利用了我們的友誼
You played on our friendship.
而現在你還讓我自說自話
And just now you had me go on about it
繼續看我的笑話
to continue the mockery.
我沒在看你的笑話
Look, I wasn't mocking you.
我只是不想讓你發現事情真相
I was trying to keep you from finding out.
我以為如果你沒發現
I thought if you didn't know,
就不會受到傷害
no harm would be done.
不  你知道嗎  傷害已經造成了
No, you know what, harm was done.
如果你還珍惜這段友誼的話
And if you value this friendship at all,
你就別插手
you would stay out of it,
因為我將針對達娜·斯科特
because I'm going to the mattresses
發起一場戰爭
against Dana Scott.
戰爭[也指床墊]
Mattresses?
你在看《教父》嗎
Have you been watching the Godfather?
對  我一直想找出些共同點
Yeah, I've been trying to come up with some common ground
來加深我們的友誼  不服告我啊
to expand our friendship-- sue me.
告訴我你已經把給富蘭克林·庫里耶的
Tell me you finished the proposal
提案寫好了
for Franklin Courier.
沒有
No.
你說沒有什么意思
What do you mean, no?
我是說我根本沒開始寫
I mean I didn't do it.
什么  你老媽去世了嗎
What, did your mother die?
因為如果她還活著  你知道
Because if she didn't, you know--
路易  是你告訴我不用寫了
Louis, you told me not to.
我們正處于戰爭狀態  班尼特
We're at war, Bennett.
我為什么要那么做
Why would I do that?
我不知道  但你給我留了張紙條
I don't know, but I got a note from you
告訴我你要做個高風亮節的人
telling me that you were gonna be the bigger person
讓達娜·斯科特來處理這個案子
and let Dana Scott handle it.
高風亮節的人
The bigger person?
你應該能猜到那不是我寫的
You should've known that was not from me.
早上好  路易  今天天氣不錯
Good morning, Louis. Great day.
你看起來有點疲倦啊
Oh, you look a little tired.
我不累  永遠感覺不到累
I'm not tired. I don't get tired.
-你想要什么  達娜  -想把這個給你
- What do you want, dana? - I'm just dropping this by.
你把提案發給富蘭克林了
You sent Franklin a proposal?
你不在場我沒法跟他們見面
Well, I couldn't meet them without you,
所有我想直接把這個發給他們算了
So I figured that I would send this over instead.
你背著我們寫了這個
You did this behind our backs.
我不喜歡背著別人辦事
I don't believe in doing things behind people's backs.
所以我把那封郵件抄送給你們倆個了
That's why I C.C.'d you both on this letter.
不  你抄送給我們
No, you C.C.'d us,
這樣他們就能知道是你發出來的
so they'd know that it came from you,
而與我們毫無關系
and we had nothing to do with it.
郵件確實是我發的
It did come from me,
而你們也確實根本沒出力
and you did have nothing to do with it.
好吧  你想這么玩嗎  沒問題
Yeah, you want to play it this way, fine.
但如果你認為自己能打敗我
But if you think you can outsmart me,
-那你得給利才行  -超級給利
- You're gonna get Litt up. - Litt the hell up.
給利
Litt up?
利特
Litt. Oh.
老天  這個好可愛
Oh, my God, that is so cute.
我一定要在臉書上記下來這個梗
I'm gonna go make fun of it on my Facebook page right now.
謝謝你們
Thank you.
這樣吧  我們要一步步奪回這個案子
Okay, we're gonna take this thing apart limb by limb
而胡說小姐會希望
so that little Miss Bullshit
她從來沒聽過路易·利特這個名字
wished she'd never heard the name Louis Litt.
路易  她是位優秀的律師
Louis, she's an excellent attorney.
如果我們找不到把柄呢
What if we can't find anything wrong with it?
我們不需要找到把柄
We're not gonna find anything wrong with it.
所以我們才要分而治之
That's why we're gonna take it apart,
創造出所謂的把柄
to make something wrong with it.
沃克先生  去年十月
Mr. Walker, in October of last year,
您曾與京都電腦公司的董事長進行過接洽
you made a pitch to the chairman of Kyoto Computers.
那次接洽怎么樣
How did that pitch go?
非常愉快
It went amazingly,
直到他們告訴我們
right up until when they told us
他們不可能購買我們的產品
there was no way they could actually buy our product.
為什么呢
And why was that?
因為亞努什威脅說
Because Janus threatened to
如果他們與我們有任何交易
withhold their microchip
亞努什將不再提供任何微芯片
if Kyoto did even $1 worth of business with us.
而我們家鄰居說
And my next-door neighbor says
他看到他老婆與鄰居偷情
he saw his next-door neighbor cheating on his wife.
而這只是個報復性的謊言
Turned out to be nothing but a vindictive lie.
這是京都公司執行總裁格里芬和霍蘭德
These are sworn affidavits from the CEOs of Kyoto, Griffon,
簽署的宣誓書  證詞與沃克先生一致
and Howland all backing up Mr. Walker's claim.
他們可不是你的鄰居  阿奇伯德
This isn't your next-door neighbor, Archibald.
沃克先生  我們占據市場支配地位
Mr. Walker, the truth is that we control the market
因為我們的產品質量比你們好  不是嗎
because our product is better than yours, isn't it?
不  不是的
No, it isn't.
得了吧  杰克  攝像頭開著呢
Jake, come on. The cameras are on.
-我們都宣誓了的  -我們都是嗎
- We're all under oath here.  - We are?
他是
He is.
我有獨立分析報告
And I have independent analysis
以及其他執行總裁的證詞
and sworn testimony from other CEOs
與您當事人的證言正好相反
disputing everything your client just said.
這些證據的證明力不值一提
Those things aren't worth the paper they're printed on.
我的意思是我們可以法庭相見
My point is that you can go to court,
為了一場你可能贏不了的官司打上數年
spend years fighting a battle you may not win,
或者接受這份和解方案
or you can take this settlement.
這方案還挺合理的
This is actually pretty fair.
何止是合理
More than fair.
只不過  他想讓我們在上面簽字
The only thing is, he's trying to get us to sign it,
然后在法庭上質證我們
so he can use it against us in court.
就像去年他對付美光科技
Just like he did last year against Micron
以及前年對付陽光科技那樣
and the year before that against Suntech.
你還真是一招吃天下  阿奇伯德
You're just a one-trick pony, Archibald.
一旦你的招數暴露  就無能為力了
And once you've been to the show, it's not that good.
你也只有一招  雷吉納德
Hmm, you're a one-trick pony too, Reginald.
只不過我的招數不會讓我的客戶起訴我
Only my trick doesn't end with my own client suing me.
-這次取證結束了  -什么叫結束了
- This deposition's over.  - What do you mean, it's over?
難道你不想讓沃克先生知道
Don't you want Mr. Walker to know
你曾被指控玩忽職守
that you were just sued for malpractice?
那名當事人撤銷了指控
That client dropped that suit.
在她撤銷之前  她曾經作出過正式聲明
And before she did, she stated on the record
稱她因你與對方律師的私人恩怨
that she got shafted because you had a personal vendetta
導致了她的利益受損
against your opposing counsel.
他喜歡在律師間尋釁滋事
He likes to pick fights with other lawyers,
不在給他的當事人帶來什么影響
and he doesn't give a shit what it does to his clients.
-一派胡言  -是嗎
- Okay, that's a lie.  - It is?
我想你我都清楚他為什么會代理這個案子
I think you and I both know why he took this case,
因為這些官司他都輸了
because he lost this case and this case
人人影視
YYeTs.com
在十五年前全都輸給了我
and this case to me 15 years ago.
快去問問他
Go ahead, ask him.
雖然他沒有宣誓  但你會看出來的
He's not under oath, but you'll know if he's lying.
而這些只是模擬法庭的案例
And these cases, they were all in moot court.
想象一下  在真實法庭上他會帶給你什么
Imagine what he'll bring down on you when the stakes are real.
我只能這樣告訴你
I can tell you this much,
它肯定比這份和解方案
it'll be a hell of a lot more expensive
要昂貴得多
than that settlement.
斯坦普爾  取證結束了
Stemple, we're done.
雷吉納德  你的確干得不錯
Reginald, you did a great job
讓我耿耿于懷
making it so I couldn't get out of it,
但你應該挑個更好的案子來對付我
but you should have picked a better case to trap me in.
因為我們都知道我的獨立分析師
Because we both know that my independent analyst
會按照我的意思出具一切報告
will come up with anything that I want him to say.
你聽到他剛剛說的話了嗎
Did you hear what he just said?
當然
I sure did.
如果你我都聽到了
And if you did, and I did...
可能它也錄到了
Maybe it did.
我已經吃過早餐了  邁克爾
I already had breakfast, Michael.
或許吧  但這可是滿滿一袋子培根
Maybe, but that's a bag completely filled with bacon.
酥脆嗎
Crispy?
引用我朋友本杰明的一句話
To quote my friend Benjamin,
無酥脆不成培根
"If it's not crispy, it's not bacon."
我不配吃它
I don't deserve it.
本杰明
Benjamin.
邁克爾  我可以從衛星傳來的音軌上
Michael, I can enhance the sound of a bee
加強蜜蜂采蜜的聲音
making pollen recorded from a satellite.
你怎么能確定
How can you possibly know that?
我做過
It's been done.
但我無法在一個二手錄像機上
But what I can't do is enhance sounds
加強一個根本沒被捕捉到的聲音
that weren't picked up by a used camcorder,
因為律所為了省錢  根本不聽我的建議
because this firm is too cheap to go with my recommendation
購置63000美元的的ZR-X90攝像機
of the $63,000 ZR-X90.
你從來沒建議過  對吧
You didn't really recommend that, did you?
還有助于我在周末拍獨立電影
It's also good for making independent films on weekends.
好了  本杰明
Okay, Benjamin,
我需要這份音軌  否則這個大案子就砸了
I need this audio, or we're screwed on a huge case.
邁克爾  看看這些聲波
Michael, look at these sound waves.
好的
Okay.
-沒有一絲變化  -什么都沒有
- There's nothing there.  - No, nothing.
這還是我連續十二個小時最大限度增強音軌
And that's after 12 hours of maximum enhancement on the tape
并喝了六罐紅牛之后的結果
and six Red Bulls in me.
你不該喝那么多紅牛
Whoa, you shouldn't be having that many Red Bulls.
這都是為了你  邁克爾
I did it for you, Michael.
有什么成果了嗎
What do we have?
沒有
Uh, nothing.
那我們只能用手里的東西了
Then we go with what we got.
他什么意思
What's he talking about?
他在說斯坦普爾嚇唬過我們
He's saying Stemple bluffed,
現在我們也要嚇唬他
so now we're gonna bluff.
先生們  我們要討論什么呢
What exactly are we talking about here, gentlemen?
我們希望得到他的獨立分析師的原始數據
We want access to the raw data from his independent analysis.
我還希望十年前做過結扎呢
And I wish I would've had a vasectomy ten years ago.
原始數據是工作成果  他無權獲得它
But raw data is work product, and he has no right to it.
成果保密權
The work product doctrine
非常明顯  斯佩克先生
is fairly clear on this, Mr. Specter.
但不適用于涉嫌欺詐情況  法官閣下
Except in cases of misconduct, Your Honor,
而目前就是這個情況
which is the situation here.
你們在指控我什么
What exactly are you accusing me of?
在取證的最后  斯坦普爾基本上在吹噓
At the end of our deposition, Mr. Stemple basically boasted
他打算修改他的分析師得出的結果
that he plans to fix the findings of his analyst.
他在說謊
That is a lie.
我從沒有說過這些話
I never said anything of the kind.
你是說
What you mean to say is
你覺得我們的攝像機沒有錄下來嗎
you didn't think our microphone would pick it up.
讓我來理清楚
So let me get this straight.
他們篡改了錄像  來指控我篡改報告
They're doctoring a tape to accuse me of doctoring a report.
斯坦普爾  你在我這里有撒謊的前科
Mr. Stemple, you have a history of lying to me.
如果你在那份錄像上
So if you're on that tape
說過任何和他們說的相近的話
saying anything close to what they're claiming,
我不但會處罰你  還會向律師委員會舉報你
I'll not only sanction you, I'll report you to the Bar.
我會給他們原始數據
I'll give them what they want.
我得承認  當我看到六億歐元時
I have to admit, when I read 600 million euros,
-還以為是個打印錯誤  -并不是
- I thought it was a typo.  - It wasn't.
波羅的海運在六個小時之內把一瓶
Baltic Freight can get a bottle of riesling
雷斯林從阿爾薩斯葡萄園運到迪拜的旅館
from an Alsatian vineyard to a Dubai hotel in six hours.
-這是偷竊  -我同意  這份計劃書
- This is a steal. - I agree. The proposal--
是自《五十度灰》以來最吸引我的東西了
most riveting thing I've read since Fifty Shades of Grey.
-但是  -但是
- But--  - But,
對您最有利的是我...
but the real upside for you is that I...
-我們  -并不是
- We.  - Not exactly.
想出了一個方案能在美國合法避稅
Structured the deal to avoid U.S. Taxes.
在塞浦路斯設立一家子公司
By setting up a subsidiary with headquarters in Cyprus.
那里的稅率只有5.7%
Where the rate is only 5.7%.
等等
Wait a second,
那不是意味著他們得在塞浦路斯建廠
doesn't that mean they would have to build in Cyprus?
我已經看好了一名開發商
Mm-hmm, and I've already locked up a developer.
我看到了  惠特納集團
Yeah, I see that, the Whitner Group.
打斷一下  你是說惠特納集團嗎
Whoa, I'm so sorry. Did you just say Whitner Group?
現在他們正因涉嫌欺詐
Right now they're being investigated
接受聯邦貿易委員會的調查
by the FTC for fraud.
什么
What?
是的  今早才宣布的消息
Yeah, it was just announced this morning.
那些肯定都是被嫉妒的競爭對手
Well, those are bogus charges concocted by a jealous competitor
不擇手段炮制出來的虛假指控
who will stop at nothing--
很抱歉  湯姆
I'm so sorry, Tom.
正如達娜剛剛說的  我只收到了抄送
As Dana mentioned, I was C.C.'d on this,
但我之前并沒有機會去審查它
but I didn't exactly have a chance to vet it.
湯姆
Tom.
名聲就是我們的一切  斯科特女士
Our reputation is everything, Ms. Scott.
我們不能和罪犯串通一氣
We can't be in bed with criminals.
我會在一小時之內給你另一份提案的
I will have another proposal over to you within the hour.
謝謝你  路易
Thank you, Louis.
對了  還有  湯姆  斯科特是新來的
Oh, and, Tom, Scottie's new, okay?
放她一馬
So just cut her some slack.
等她能獨當一面的時候
Because when those training wheels pop off,
她會很棒的
she's gonna be really, really good.
-你做了什么  -什么也沒做
- What the hell did you do?  - Nothing.
我只是給聯邦貿易委員會的朋友打了個電話
I just called a friend at the FTC.
你捏造了一個起訴來對付一家公司
You made up charges against a company
就是為了對付我
just to get back at me?
我才沒做過這種事呢
I did nothing of the kind.
我只是簡單地提醒了一個朋友
I simply alerted a friend
說了說一些可能的不軌行為
to some possible misdoings.
那可都是人啊
These are people.
你損害了他們的生意
You are hurting their business.
拜托  饒了我吧
Oh, please, give me a break.
他們又沒上市
They're not publicly traded.
也沒有股價給他們下跌
They don't have a stock price that'll fall.
而且假如他們像你宣稱的一樣正經
And if they're as clean as you say,
我確定他們會擺脫指控的
I'm sure they'll be exonerated.
但不會是富蘭克林的案子還在我手上期間
But not in time for me to get Franklin's business.
我才不在乎他們什么時候擺脫
Oh, I don't give a shit when they're exonerated.
你永遠拿不到富蘭克林的案子
You're never getting Franklin's business.
你真是個賤人
You really are a dick.
我是個白鯨級別的大賤人
I'm Moby Goddamn Dick,
Moby Dick: 《白鯨記》(世界名著)
而你剛剛不知好歹闖進我的水域了
and you just swam in my waters.
按照你的要求  全部都在這里了
Per your request, this is everything.
你來這里不止是為了送工作成果的吧
You didn't just come over here to deliver work product.
我收到了一份修改后的和解協議
I've got a revised settlement offer.
先讓我把話說完
And before you say anything,
這里面有個禁止我用這個來起訴你的條款
it contains a provision prohibiting me from using it against you.
在今天發生的事情之后
After what happened today,
你還覺得我會同意和解嗎
you think I'm going to settle?
拜托了  哈維  你就看一眼吧
Please, Harvey, just take a look at it.
現在你有求于我了
So now that you need something,
就喊我哈維而不是雷吉納德了
it's Harvey, not Reginald.
你不正是想要和解嗎
Settling is what you do.
但不是和你
Not with you.
至于我不愿和你和解的原因...
And the reason I'm not gonna settle with you--
人人影視
YYeTs.com
我知道
I get it.
因為我一直躲著你
I ducked you.
我能接受失敗
Look, I could take the losing,
接受別人的幸災樂禍和各種嘲諷
the gloating, and the taunting.
但我不能忍受的  是輸給一個不敢站起來
But what I can't take is losing to a coward
努力再打敗我一次的懦夫
who's too afraid to stand up and try to beat me again.
我從來沒打敗過你
I didn't beat you the first time.
你在說什么鬼呢
What the hell are you talking about?
那次是設計好的
It was rigged.
我賄賂了陪審團
I bribed the jury.
-什么  -這就是我一直躲著你的原因
- What?  - That's why I keep ducking you.
你是在告訴我你三年來一直在作弊嗎
You're telling me you cheated all three years?
一旦我贏了
Once I won,
我就是那個打敗哈維·斯佩克特的人了
I was the guy who beat Harvey Specter.
沒辦法回頭了
There was no going back.
而你覺得現在和我坦白能讓我接受和解嗎
And you think admitting that now is gonna make me settle?
我坦白是因為現在是時候讓自己心安一點了
I'm coming clean because it's time to put it to bed.
讓自己心安一點
Put it to bed?
你是打算在報紙上登廣告說你作弊嗎
You gonna take an AD out in the Crims saying you cheated,
就如同當年你打敗我時那樣嗎
just like you did when you beat me back then?
-哈維  -不不  我記的可清楚了
- Harvey.  - No, no, I remember it.
拳王阿里站在拳王利斯頓旁邊
Muhammad Ali standing over Sonny Liston.
你的臉安在了阿里身上
Your face on Ali,
我的臉安在了利斯頓身上
mine on Liston,
那一周每天都登了這幅圖
Every day for a week.
你知道我心目中的英雄是誰嗎  艾略特
You know who my hero was, Eliot?
阿里
Ali.
沒錯  你個混蛋
That's right, you piece of shit.
你想知道我為何要那么做嗎
You want to know why I did that?
因為你說個傲慢的混蛋
Because you were an arrogant bastard
生活瀟灑  對什么事都漫不經心
who skated through life without a care in the world,
從你需要的任何人手中拿到你想要的一切
Getting everything you wanted from anyone you needed!
還有  你知道嗎
And you know what,
假如再來一次
if I had to do it again,
我還會那么做的
I would do the exact same thing.
我不會和解的
I'm not settling.
只要你有一點違法的想法
You so much as think about breaking the law on this case,
我保證你最后會進監獄的
I guarantee you'll end up in jail.
-這是...  -沒錯
- Is this-- - Yes.
-加了...  -是的
- With extra-- - Yes.
-我為何享有如此殊榮  -達娜·斯科特
- To what do I owe this honor? - Dana Scott.
-不行  -聽我說完
- No. - Hear me out.
你贏了
You won.
我不是要你向她屈服
I'm not saying you have to give in to her.
我是要你修補一下你倆的關系
I'm saying, make amends with her.
那我為什么要這么做呢
Mm, and why would I want to do that?
假如你能站在她的角度思考問題
Well, it would help if you tried
會有很大幫助的
putting yourself in her shoes.
站在她試圖拐跑我的客戶的角度嗎
The same shoes that tried walking away with my client?
路易  我想說的就是
Louis, all I'm saying is,
她從達比國際跳槽來這里
she came here from Darby International
就為了當哈維的女朋友
to be Harvey's girlfriend.
這個就足夠分量
I'd say that's enough baggage
讓你放她一馬了
to deserve you cutting her some slack.
但我確實已經放了她一馬了啊  唐娜
But I did cut her some slack, Donna.
我給她買了世界上最好的披肩
I bought her the world's finest pashmina,
但反過來她卻用那個來擦屁股
and she wiped her ass with it in return.
行了  我明白了
Okay, I got it.
你永遠也不會喜歡她的
You're never gonna like her.
就當我什么也沒說吧
Forget I said anything.
等等
Wait a second.
是哈維派你來的嗎
Did harvey send you here?
不是  路易  他沒派我來
No, Louis, he didn't.
哈維才不關心這種事呢
Harvey doesn't care about this.
那你為什么關心這個呢
Why do you?
因為我了解哈維  我了解斯科特
Because I know Harvey, I know Scottie,
我也了解你
and I know you.
如果沒人讓步的話
And if somebody doesn't back down,
這件事不會有好結果的
this isn't gonna end well.
你是說你或者哈維
Are you saying that you or Harvey
會拿這個來對付我嗎
are gonna hold this against me?
不是  路易  我沒這么說
No, Louis, I'm not saying that.
那就好  因為這樣的話
Good, because then
我就要和你學學我對他說的話了
I'll tell you what I told him.
假如我們的友誼就靠這個
If our friendship is dependent on this,
那我們之間就沒有友誼可言了
then we do not have a friendship at all.
不是的
It's not.
我只是想幫忙而已
I was just trying to help.
莫里斯先生
Mr. Morris,
請你告訴法庭  原始數據說明了
please tell the court what the raw data indicates
這兩個公司的微處理器的什么問題
about the two companies' microprocessors.
而且我要提醒你  你是宣過誓的
And I remind you, you're under oath.
兩個產品運行于相同的速度
Both products operate at the exact same rate.
你的意思是
What you're saying is,
我們的產品和他們不相上下
our product is just as good as theirs.
我的意思是  他們的表現是相同的
I'm saying their performance is identical.
而且亞努什在市場上占主導地位
And yet Janus dominates the marketplace.
為什么會這樣呢
Why is that?
反對  這是要求證人作出推測
Objection. Calls for speculation.
讓我來告訴你為什么
Oh, I'll tell you why.
這和產品的優越性毫無關系
It has nothing to do with product superiority
一切都是亞努什在欺壓他的競爭對手
and everything to do with Janus bullying its competitors.
你剛剛既不是在提問
That's not a question,
你所說的和莫里斯先生的專業領域無關
nor is it Mr. Morris' area of expertise.
對  的確無關
No, it isn't.
恃強凌弱是他客戶的專業領域
Bullying is his client's area of expertise.
暫無其他問題
No further questions.
莫里斯先生  你剛剛指證
Mr. Morris, you just testified
兩種微處理器的表現是相同的
that the microprocessors' performance was identical.
那有沒有可能他們實際上就是雷同的呢
Is it possible that they are actually identical?
任何事都是有可能的
Anything's possible.
在什么情況下才有可能呢
How would that be?
這要么是一個極小概率事件
Either it's a one-in-a-billion event,
要么是一方偷了另一方的設計
or one of them stole the other one's design.
法官大人  基于對方律師引入的證據
Your honor, based on evidence introduced by opposing counsel
以及莫里斯先生的作證
and Mr. Morris' testimony,
我希望提出反訴
I would like to file a countersuit
控告AYZ科技侵犯專利權
Against AYZ for patent infringement.
這簡直是離譜
That is outrageous.
他的客戶剽竊了我的客戶的設計
His client stole my client's design.
我才是該憤怒的人
I am the one who is outraged.
這案子和侵犯專利權半點關系都沒有
This case has nothing to do with patent infringement.
現在有關系了  雷吉納德
It does now, Reginald.
讓開
Move!
我們得談談
We need to talk.
現在不行  我在補充碳水化合物
Not now, I'm carbo-loading.
為了什么
For what?
為了你啊  我們還在交戰呢
For you! We're still at war.
不  才沒有
No, we're not.
那什么意思
So what,
你在揮旗求饒嗎
you're telling me you're waving the white flag?
不是  我在揮舞這個
No, I am waving this,
公司章程第19.5條B款
bylaw 19.5/B,
明顯違背第139條J款
in clear violation of 139/J.
我得到了139條J款的通過
I got ratification per 139J.
法定人數未達到
There wasn't a quorum present.
沒什么大礙  技術犯規而已
Big deal, technical violation.
對你可不一樣  你是章程委員會的
Not for you. You're on the bylaw committee.
你知道章程中對于委員會成員
And you know what the bylaws say about a member of the committee
私自執行未經批準的修正案怎么處理吧
implementing an amendment without approval?
立即除名
Immediate removal.
所以你離我的案子遠點
So back the hell off my case.
這靠不住的
This won't stand.
路易  我警告你別繼續糾纏
Louis, I am warning you to not keep pursuing this.
我之前贏過你  不介意再贏一次
I've beaten you before, and I will beat you again.
人人影視
YYeTs.com
-你才沒贏過我  -沒有嗎
- You've never beaten me before. - Haven't I?
那你覺得是誰讓奈杰爾
Who do you think it was that assigned Nigel
在解約談判上和你對抗的
to go against you in the dissolution talks?
喵嗚
Meow.
-你這個魔鬼  -不
- You're the devil. - No.
我不是魔鬼  我只是講究策略
I'm not the devil. I'm a strategic thinker.
路易·利特  我特此通知你
Louis Litt, you are hereby notified
在富蘭克林·庫里耶一案中
that your services are no longer needed
不再需要你了
on Franklin Courier.
如果你再來煩我
And if you go around me,
我就用139條J款把你殺得片甲不留
I will invoke 139J on your ass.
他暗算我們
He set us up.
你以為我看不出來嗎
You think I don't know that?
他弄得我們的客戶像個竊賊一樣
He made our client look like a thief.
分明就是騙人
It's not true.
是真是假已經不重要了
It doesn't matter if it's not true.
我們現在處于被動
Now we're on the defensive.
先生們  和解條件
Gentlemen, that settlement offer
已經不再適用了
is about to get flipped on its ass.
多謝你們引入的證據
And thank you for introducing that evidence,
由我說出來的話就沒這么可信了
'cause it wouldn't have been as credible coming from me.
你使計套我們的話
You dropped that comment on purpose.
我知道攝像機不會錄下這段
Mm-hmm. I knew that camcorder wouldn't pick it up,
我也知道你會嚇唬我說要拿到證據
just like I knew you would bluff to get that data.
是你算計我們了  不然我們早料到了
You made us work for it, or we would've seen it coming.
他才不會料到
He would never have seen anything coming
我之前騙他說我賄賂陪審團了
once I fed him that bullshit about bribing the jury.
我太了解你了  雷吉納德
I've got your number, Reginald.
我可沒陷害你  只是略施小計而已
I haven't been ducking you. I've just been setting you up.
這都是跟你的偶像學的
I took a page from your hero's playbook,
伺機反攻
Rope-a-dope.
我都聽說了
I heard about today.
即使你沒聽說
If you hadn't,
明天也能從報紙上看到
I'm sure there'll be an ad about it in the paper tomorrow.
什么
What?
斯坦普爾說他對我了如指掌  說的沒錯
Stemple says he's got my number, and it's true.
我不知道該怎么辦了
I don't know what to do.
我們有什么選擇嗎
What are our options?
就我所知  接受和解是最優方案了
For all I know, this deal's the best I'm ever going to get.
斯坦普爾每次都考慮得先我一步
Stemple's been outthinking me ever since I met him.
除了他  也就你能這樣了
You're the only other person who's ever done that.
我需要你的幫助
I need your help.
我跟你說過我高中時打網球的經歷嗎
Have I ever told you about my high school tennis career?
我都不知道你會打網球
I didn't even know you played.
我的成績是38勝3負
I was 38 and 3.
知道我輸給了誰嗎
You know who handed me every one of those losses?
艾略特·斯丹普爾嗎
Eliot Stemple?
瑪莎·邁耶斯
Marsha Myers.
一個身高五英尺[152cm]的數學怪咖
A 5-foot-nothing math geek
發球速度每小時20英里[32公里]
with a 20-mile-an-hour serve.
我應該在球場上
I should have left a Marsha Myers skid mark
留個瑪莎·邁耶斯的標記  永不回望
on the court and never looked back.
但是實際上  她簡直就是個回球機器
But instead, the little bitch was a human backboard.
時至今日我仍然無法忘記
And I think about it to this day.
你是建議我接受交易
You're saying I should take the deal
因為我贏不了他
because I can't beat him?
我只是說有個艾略特·斯丹普爾這樣的人
I'm saying I know what it's like
我理解你的心情
to have an Eliot Stemple.
我問你個問題
So I'm going to ask you a question,
我要你立刻回答
and I want you to give me an instant response.
你是想擊敗他  還是想和解
Do you want to beat him, or do you want to settle?
我想留個艾略特·斯坦普爾的標記
I want to leave an Eliot Stemple skid mark.
那就有答案了
Then there's your answer.
如果他對你了如指掌
If he's got your number,
那么你想做的  就是他想要你做的
then what you want to do is what he wants you to do.
哈維  我一直在研究斯坦普爾的案子
Harvey, I've been looking at Stemple's cases.
沒必要了
Doesn't matter.
沒必要了是什么意思
What do you mean it doesn't matter?
我們接受和解條件
We're taking the settlement.
-你就這么放棄了嗎  -杰西卡有個計劃
- You're just gonna give up? - Jessica has a plan.
繼續抗爭下去只能是自投羅網
Fighting is stepping into a trap.
一步步走進他安排的陷阱
We'd be giving him exactly what he wants.
杰西卡錯了
Jessica was wrong.
是這樣嗎
Is that a fact?
你分析問題的角度是對的
You looked at it the right way.
但結論是錯的
You just came to the wrong conclusion.
斯坦普爾是想讓我們繼續  但我知道原因
Stemple wants us to fight, but I know why.
他接手這案子很久了
He was on this case
遠比我們介入的早
long before you and I came into the picture.
他想要的  他真正想要的
What he wants... what he really wants...
其實跟你無關
has nothing to do with you.
你這是準備好大干一場了
Don't you look ready to rumble?
不是
We're not.
我們接受你的條件  但有一點要改
We want to take your deal, with one small change.
我不會降低金額的
I'm not lowering the amount.
這你不必擔心  你要求一千萬美元
No, don't worry. Instead of $10 million,
我們給你一億美元
we'd like to give you 100 million.
即使這么多  也比不上和你打下去
Because that would still cost us less
讓你得到這個  給我們造成的損失
than if we fought you and you got this.
我不知道這是什么
I have no idea what that is.
你心知肚明
Yes, you do.
正是這個膠水  使得AYZ科技
It's the glue that enables AYZ
能夠堆棧比你們更多的微芯片
to stack more microchips than you,
你找這東西已經一年了
and you've been after it for a year.
你猜到了我的舉動以后
And when you saw me coming,
趁機誘騙我
you used the opportunity to bait me
讓我引用證據
into introducing evidence
你得以翻盤  并提起訴訟
so that you could turn it around and manufacture a suit
以便順利得到這東西
to get your hands on that during discovery.
你沒證據
You can't prove that.
如果我問你的分析師當初你聘用他的原因
I can when I ask your analyst
我就能得到證據了
why you hired him in the first place.
他會說亞努什需要這個技術
He's gonna say that Janus needed the technology
不惜一切代價
and was willing to do anything to get it.
你不確定他會供出我
You don't know that he'll roll over on me.
阿里對陣利斯頓
Ali versus Liston.
我會讓他供出你
I'm gonna make him roll over on you.
接下來我建議你
So here's what's gonna happen.
放棄訴訟
You're gonna drop the suit,
公開聲明承認過錯  賠償我們這些金額
publicly admit to wrongdoing, and pay us this.
這可讓我的客戶損失大了
This'll cost my client a fortune.
是啊  但總比被判成
Yeah, but it's better than being convicted
商業間諜罪要好
of corporate espionage.
艾略特  我可是想讓你體面的退出
Eliot, I'm giving you a dignified way out,
一個真正了解的機會
a chance to really put it to bed.
再有三十秒  法官就要開庭了
Now the judge is gonna bang that gavel in 30 seconds.
一旦開庭  一切都不可挽救了
And when that happens, it's gonna be too late.
成交
We'll take the deal.
我說  如果你想引用個電影情節的話
I'm just saying, if you're gonna quote a movie,
就原話引用
Quote a movie.
就說錯了一個詞
I got one word wrong.
整個引用都沒有意義了
It changed the entire meaning of the quote.
我可沒覺得
Not to me, it didn't.
我以為原話就這樣
That's what I thought the quote was.
好吧
Okay, fine.
如果你不尊重馬丁·斯科西斯的話
You want to be disrespectful to Martin Scorsese,
人人影視
YYeTs.com
那隨你吧
you go right ahead.
劇本又不是馬丁·斯科西斯寫的
Martin Scorsese didn't even write the damn movie.
就算不尊重  也是不尊重編劇
If anything, it's disrespectful to the writer.
哈維  沒人在乎編劇是誰
Harvey, who cares about the writer?
這話有道理
I guess you're right about that.
-你們去哪兒了  -請他去吃飯了
- Where have you two been? - I took him to dinner.
這倒是挺新鮮啊
Oh, that's never happened before.
他從來沒贏過A.艾略特·斯坦普爾  對吧
Well, he's never beaten A.Eliot Stemple before.
沒贏過
No, he hasn't.
那這次有什么不同呢
What could be different about this time?
我當時沒為他工作
I didn't work for him then.
但有你在的時候
Yeah, but didn't he duck Harvey
他不是一直在躲著哈維嗎
the whole time you did work for him?
好吧
Okay, fine.
打敗斯坦普爾是你的功勞
You were responsible for beating Stemple,
但是最開始是我告訴你哈維那幾次
but I was the one who told you about Harvey's shameful losses
慘敗事跡的
in the first place.
他常說的那句話怎么說來著
What does he always say?
零對無數  唐娜  零對無數
0 and everything, Donna. 0 and everything.
說完了嗎
Are you finished?
是的  謝謝
Yes, thank you.
對了  杰西卡讓你回來以后
Oh, and Jessica wanted to see you
盡快去找她
as soon as you got back.
她說是因為什么事情了嗎
She say what it's about?
沒有  但我是在跟邁克講話
No, but I was talking to Mike.
我聽說你贏了
I heard you won.
-我們不只是贏了  -我知道
- Oh, we didn't just win. - I know.
你讓一個財富500強公司公開承認過錯
You got a fortune 500 company to publicly admit wrongdoing.
這可不是每天都有的事情
Doesn't happen every day.
那你怎么還看起來不高興呢
So why don't you look happy?
贏了官司我很高興
I am happy about the win.
但我接到了《紐約律師》編輯的電話
But I got a call from the editor of New York Lawyer,
他們想采訪這次
and they want to interview the man responsible
訴訟的負責人
for making that happen.
然后你想把功勞都給哈維
And you want to give Harvey the credit.
我想讓你把自己的名字撤下來
I want you to take your name off.
我已經那么做了
I already did.
這個案子本身就不是為了我  是為哈維
This case was never for me. It was for harvey.
斯坦普爾上鉤的那一刻起
I took my name off as first chair
我就把自己的名字從第一律師上撤了下來
the second we trapped Stemple.
很感謝你那么做了
I appreciate that.
但因為這個采訪  你無法以任何身份出現
But because of this interview, you can't be any chair.
所以你讓我從這個案子上撤下來
So you don't want me off this case
不是為了把功勞給哈維
so that Harvey can get the credit.
你把我撤下來
You want me off this case,
是為了讓我遠離聚光燈
so I don't get anywhere near the spotlight.
從你的角度出發
In your position,
聚光燈可以很快的
the spotlight can become an interrogation lamp
變成審訊燈
pretty damn fast.
我理解
I understand.
不要聚光燈
No spotlight.
本來就會是這樣  對嗎
This is always how it's gonna be, isn't it?
我以為你知道
I thought you knew that.
我知道
I guess I did.
能和你談談嗎
Hey, can I talk to you?
當然  路易  有什么可以效勞的
Sure, Louis. What can I do for you?
你肯定聽說了達娜·斯科特搶我客戶的事
Um, I'm sure you heard about Dana Scott's throttling of me.
還沒有
I haven't.
你們兩個都想我不要干預  所以我沒有
You both wanted me to stay out of it, and I did.
對的
Right.
斯科特搶了我的案子后  我去找杰西卡
See, after Scottie took my case, I went to Jessica.
我是想去斗個你死我活的  她跟我說
I was after blood, and... she told me--
她跟我說這些事是我自找的
she told me that I bring these things on myself,
她說得對
and she was right.
那也讓我開始思考  如果我沒有遲到
And that got me to wondering, what would've happened
會發生什么事情
if I hadn't shown up to that meeting late?
所以我去了閱覽室
So I went to the library,
找了本公司章程
and I found a copy of the bylaws.
斯科特劃出了六個不同的陷阱
Scottie underlined six different traps.
她就是故意要讓我難堪的
She deliberately picked a fight to embarrass me,
我想知道你知不知情
and I want to know if you knew.
她那么做不是為了讓你難堪
She didn't do it to embarrass you.
她是想打敗律所里最兇最毒的律師
She wanted to beat the meanest, toughest guy at the firm.
-好吧  -這是出于一種敬意
- Okay. - It's a sign of respect.
但這種情況的問題所在是
See, the problem with that is,
當那個人輸了以后  他就完蛋了
when that guy loses... he's done.
他就再也不是律所里最兇最毒的律師了
He is no longer the meanest, baddest guy in the firm.
他就一無是處了
He's nothing.
路易
Louis...
你想讓我怎么做
What do you want from me?
我想讓你利用你的力量
I need you to use your power
從斯科特那里幫我把案子搶過來
to give me this case over Scottie.
我不能那么做
I can't do that.
哈維  她輸了沒關系  但我不行
Harvey, she can survive this. I can't.
-路易  -聽著  你來找我
- Louis-- - Listen, you came to me
需要我幫忙的時候說我是你的朋友
and said I was your friend when you needed a favor.
現在我來找你了
Well, I am now coming to you,
說我也需要你的幫忙
saying that I need a favor in return.
上次我們談這事的時候
The last time we talked,
你說如果我珍視我們的友誼
you said if I value our friendship at all,
那我就不會干預這件事
I'd stay out of it.
我不在乎
I don't care.
我知道你的做事風格
I know how you operate.
我為你放了邁克一馬
I let it go with Mike for you.
而我現在要求你做的事情
And what I'm asking for in return
根本無法與那件事相提并論  所以
doesn't even come close, so...
那確實是我的做事風格  路易
I do operate that way, louis,
但和朋友不是那樣
but not with my friends.
所以我只問你一次
So I'm only gonna ask you this once.
你是作為朋友求我  還是讓我還人情
Are you asking as a friend, or are you calling in a chit?
還人情
I'm calling in a chit.
那好吧
So be it.
-你生氣了嗎  -我很失望
- Are you mad? - I'm disappointed.
哈維  我
Harvey, I--
你不能二者兼得  路易
You can't have it both ways, Louis.
家具到了
The furniture came.
我知道我們之前說都聽我的
Look, I know we said that we'd go with all my choices,
但看來你的品位還不錯
but it turns out you have got pretty good taste.
是啊  我有
Yes. Yes, I do.
所以  你覺得怎么樣
So? What do you think?
我覺得我簡直不敢相信
I think that I can't believe
你在一天之內做了這么多事
you did all of this in one day.
我回家以后就一直在忙
Well, I've been working on it since I got home.
我只是想趕快弄完
I just wanted to have all of it ready,
好慶祝你的勝利
so we could celebrate your big win.
哈維開心嗎
Was Harvey appreciative?
當然了  他還帶我去吃晚餐了
Yeah, are you kidding? He took me out to dinner.
晚餐啊
Oh! Dinner.
下一件事就是升職了
Next thing you know, you'll be getting a promotion.
是啊  下一件
Yeah. Next thing.
-你好  -你也好
- Hey. - Hey, yourself.
我希望你不介意我自己開門進來了
I hope you don't mind that I let myself in.
準備好慶祝了嗎
You ready to celebrate?
-準備好喝一杯了  -那可要快點
- I'm ready for a drink. - Well, hurry up.
因為這件衣服下
Because underneath these clothes,
我可是全裸
I am entirely naked.
斯科特
Scottie.
怎么了
What's wrong?
你之前心情還很好啊
You were in such a good mood earlier.
發生了什么事
What happened?
是很好
I was.
但是呢
But?
斯科特  我需要你把案子還給路易
Scottie, I need you to give Louis his transaction back.
什么
What?
他發現整件事都是你陷害他的
He figured out that you set the whole thing up,
然后來找我了
and he came to me.
所以呢
So what?
那有什么關系呢
What does that have to do with anything?
你輸了沒關系  他不行
You can survive this. He can't.
等等  讓我理一下
Wait, so let me get this straight.
路易說如果我輸了
Louis tells me that if I lose
我不能跑去找我的男朋友
I can't go running to my boyfriend,
但他轉身就去做了同樣的事
and then he turned around and does the exact same thing?
斯科特  我需要你這么做
Scottie, I need you to do this.
這和他之前幫你的那個忙有關系嗎
Does this have something to do with that favor he did you?
是的
Yes.
好  那告訴我是什么事
Okay. Tell me what it is.
不行
I can't.
看來我們根本不是
Guess we're not sharing everything
分享所有秘密了
with each other after all.
斯科特
Scottie.
哈維  在你開口之前
Harvey, before you say what you're about to say,
我需要知道
I need to know.
我是在和我的男朋友講話
Am I talking to my boyfriend,
還是在和冠名合伙人講話
or am I talking to a name partner?
那要看你的回答是什么
That depends on your answer.
你不能二者兼得  哈維
You can't have it both ways, Harvey.
那你就是在和冠名合伙人講話
Then you're talking to a name partner.